<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Curtis Ullerich</title>
 <link href="http://www.curtisullerich.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.curtisullerich.com"/>
 <updated>2013-02-11T00:02:32-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.curtisullerich.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Curtis Ullerich</name>
   <email>curtisu@iastate.edu</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Jekyll Picasa Album with Fancybox</title>
   <link href="http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/12/albums"/>
   <updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/12/albums</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This website is created with Jekyll. I&amp;#8217;ve done a lot to customize it from the original Jekyll Bootstrap, starting with Bootswatch, and more recently with plugins. On my photography pages I have photo albums. Previously, I used the &lt;a href='http://code.google.com/p/pwi/'&gt;Picasa Webalbum Integrator&lt;/a&gt; which did a great job. I wanted to be able to do soemthing cleaner, though, now that I&amp;#8217;m using Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was already using the &lt;a href='http://www.pztrick.com/blog/2012/06/26/jekyll-fancyimage-tag/'&gt;&lt;code&gt;fancyimage&lt;/code&gt; tag&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Paul for automated thumbnail generation, which used fancybox to display images when clicked. It had support for galleries, but only for a pre-existing list of links to images. See his post for full usage instructions. Note that thumbnails, once generated, are not automatically deleted if they are not referenced, so it&amp;#8217;s good practice to clear the folder every once in a while, and they&amp;#8217;ll just regenerate next time you run Jekyll. While this worked out-of-the-box to generate the thumbnails for me, he doesn&amp;#8217;t describe how to load up Fancybox. Luckily, &lt;a href='http://www.granneman.com/webdev/coding/css/fancybox-a-better-lightbox/'&gt;great documentation&lt;/a&gt; already exists for that. If, like me, you&amp;#8217;re using a version of jQuery on your site other than that used by Fancybox, you&amp;#8217;ll get to learn about jQuery&amp;#8217;s noConflict magic. This allows you to use multiple versions of jQuery if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='javascript'&gt;&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nx'&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nx'&gt;language&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;Javascript&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nx'&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='kd'&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nx'&gt;fancy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nx'&gt;jQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nx'&gt;noConflict&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='nx'&gt;fancy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nb'&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nx'&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='kd'&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class='nx'&gt;jQuery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;.fancybox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nx'&gt;fancybox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='p'&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='lineno'&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='err'&gt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To match PWI&amp;#8217;s automatic album inclusion, I found Michael Scherer&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='https://github.com/schmic/jekyll-picasa-album-tag'&gt;picasa album tag&lt;/a&gt; Jekyll plugin. If you have problems running it, make sure you have &lt;a href='http://nokogiri.org/tutorials/installing_nokogiri.html'&gt;Nokoguri&lt;/a&gt; installed. In his original script, there&amp;#8217;s also a typo that caused the closing gallery tag to not be included. See my &lt;a href='https://github.com/schmic/jekyll-picasa-album-tag/pull/1'&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; for the fix if it hasn&amp;#8217;t been merged already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My setup in _config.yml:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='yaml'&gt;&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;picasa_album&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;thumbnail_size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;gallery_tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;gallery_class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;gallery&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;a_rel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;fancybox&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;a_class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;fancybox&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use it, just grab the RSS url of any public Picasa album.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>TBS Website Rebuild</title>
   <link href="http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/11/tbs_website"/>
   <updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/11/tbs_website</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m currently the Tau Beta Sigma webmaster. During winter break I finally had time to give the website the attention it needed to standardize and clean up everything. Overall, the original design was clean, but after a couple of webmasters without previous web design experience, things had gotten a little hairy. In some places the CSS had become very hacky and most of the pages actually had invalid HTML that just happened to render nicely in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up redesigning the site from the ground up, re-implementing the CSS using some CSS3 goodies and fixing some irregularities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot in the process, and am now confident that I could design a simple site from scratch on my own, which is something I wasn&amp;#8217;t confident I could do previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched from the old web album library that required using an external application to generate a bunch of files to using lightbox2, with a PHP script to generate the album page given a directory name with the photos. In order to make it efficient, though, I do still generate thumbnails using imagemagick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest switch was from using static member profile pages to dynamic. I created a json file that contains all of the profile information per member and two PHP files: one for the directory page and one for a profile. The directory page reads and sorts all entries, formatting them into a table and inserting links to each profile. The profile page uses URL parameters to locate the member&amp;#8217;s information in the json file and populate the page with all the information, properly excluding any missing information, and uses a default image if one is not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because SLOC is always the best metric for project &amp;lt;/sarcam&amp;gt;, here are some stats about the lines of original source (not including libraries):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th /&gt;&lt;th&gt;before&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;after&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;php&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;4117&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;595&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;css&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;241&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;136&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;json&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;537&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;other&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;2242&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;total&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;6600&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style='text-align: left;'&gt;1384&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the lines of PHP are the total for PHP files, which are mostly HTML in the end. The lines also don&amp;#8217;t count the Javascript/CSS used in either the original or new photo album libraries. The &amp;#8220;other&amp;#8221; lines in the old site are due to some extra config files, txt, and html files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new implementation of member profiles cut down on a lot of duplication, but more importantly, it standardized the pages and made it trivially easy to add new members to the site or move their profiles to different pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the rebuild, I was able to reduce the site&amp;#8217;s lines of code by 79%! My goal with the redesign was to make it trivially easy for me to maintain, and very easy for future webmasters to udpate and extend. I learned a lot and had some fun. All in all, a good two days. You can check out the results &lt;a href='http://music.iastate.edu/org/kkytbs/tbs/'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RTcmix</title>
   <link href="http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/09/rtcmix"/>
   <updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.curtisullerich.com/projects/2013/01/09/rtcmix</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During winter break I have been learning about algorithmic composition using &lt;a href='http://www.rtcmix.org/'&gt;RTcmix&lt;/a&gt; (with a Python front-end). Someone on their mailing list suggested Heinrich Taube&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Notes from the Metalevel&amp;#8221; as an introductory text on the subject. Because that book uses Lisp, I translated many of the examples into Python with RTcmix for sound generation. I implemented several functions from the Common Music API as well, most notably nth-order Markov chaining. You can see the code on &lt;a href='http://www.github.com/curtisullerich/cmix'&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>